Yeah, so this was in 2015 and this was maybe a year after I actually started to make more movement.
A Jason artwork and collaborative movement art.
And so when I was in the Bay Area for a few months, you know, I met folks like Micah Bazant who is now a really dear friend.
Micah.
What took me to like all of these different events and conversations that were have political conversations that were happening in the city of Oakland and.
I just remember being at.
I cannot remember the name of the conversation, but I remember it was different community organizers talking about.
I was a person abolition and.
It might have been a critical resistance conversation honestly and I was still.
I had really focused on police abolition and I was really.
I had organized with obviously we charged on a side was 2014 and so like I was really.
I was a person that was in that world, but prison abolition was something new for me.
And so as I was listening to this conversation, I started to draw.
So this was just drawn with you know, micro pen and paper on a scratch sheet of paper that I had.
And I just started drawing and.
I just started to draw.
And I was like, I think I just wanted to see these these prison bars being pulled by different hands are different arms pulling them all different ways.
And then you see these birds just sort of like coming out from the depths of it out of the out of the image.
And then I just really wanted to emphasize that prison abolition isn't going to happen in a silo it's not going to happen just with one person.
Making it happen it's going to take all of us to sort of pull at the system and various ways at various angles with various tactics and I think.
And we'll like our people be able to be free and and and to thrive because I and into into sort of go out into the world and and and exist and.
I think it's just like as simple as that and I just wanted it to keep it simple and not add words or add you know.
I even want to add abolition now to the piece itself because I just wanted it to have this visual effect of liberating.
Of liberation right but as again as a collective effort.
Because I did it first in in a little bit of pencil and then I think when I went to I think I actually drew the birds first and then I drew the.
The bars and the hands after.
And I had a little ruler with me, which is why the some of the outline is pretty straight but.
Yeah, so I think the birds were drawn first.
And then I think it's really important to be restrained into this box because I think if it didn't have that bird at the top.
It would it would just for me it would just mean that.
There people are still inside that you're just sort of like almost like a prison reform right like like OK, well we're giving them a little bit of freedom like.
You know, you a little bit more right but I wanted it to show like no like.
So it's all from this space.